

Aliasghar Momeni Vesalian

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - JAVA

PROFILE

Gender: Male

Nationality: Persian **Birth Date**: 6/30/1985

Software engineer with a strong background in design and development on Java platform for more than 15 years. Keen learner and problem solver with a passion for algorithms, architecture, high throughput systems and Big Data. Highly experienced in developing financial and banking systems.

EDUCATION

Master of Science from Tehran Markazi Azad University in Software Engineering from September 2015 to Present.

Bachelor of Science from Qazvin Azad University in Software Engineering from September 2003 to September 2008.

LANGUAGES

English

Persian

CONTACT

Email: momeni.vesalian@gmail.com

Mobile: +49 176 57799773

LinkedIn: Momeni Vesalian's profile

Address: Voltairestraße 11, 10179

Berlin, Germany

WORK EXPERIENCE

Wayfair

Senior Software Engineer

May 2022 - Present

- I design, implement, and deploy facility service.
- I design, implement, and deploy shipment service.

Delivery Hero

Senior Software Engineer

Jul 2020 - May 2022

- I design, implement, and deploy order transmission service.

EPAM Systems

Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2019 - May 2020

- As a key developer, I design and implement a search project.
- As a key developer, I design and implement a web crawler project.

Sava Arman Kish (Bitex)

Senior Java Developer

Jun 2018 - Mar 2019

- I worked as the chief architect of the exchange project.
- I designed the architecture model and implemented architectural APIs.
- I designed and implemented the matching engine.

Navaco (Maskan Bank)

Senior Java Developer

Mar 2017 - Jun 2018

- I worked as a member of CORE Banking architecture team.
- I designed the architecture model and implemented some architectural APIs.
- I designed and implemented lending overnight calculation.

Caspian (Parsian Bank)

Senior Java Developer and Designer

Sep 2009 - Mar 2017

- I worked as a member of the Lending team.
- I designed and implemented conversion's architecture model.
- I designed and implemented repayment, settlement, and installment calculation.



Aliasghar Momeni Vesalian

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - JAVA

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Java 17	Spring
Design Patterns	Spring Boot
Microservices	Spring MVC
Event Driven Architecture	Spring Batch / Quartz
Software Architecture Patterns	Spring Security
Algorithms / Data Structures	Spring Data / JPA
Distributed Systems	Spring Statemachine
High Frequency, Availability, Scalable	Spring WebFlux
Fault-tolerant and Low-Latency Systems	Vert.x
Multi-Threading and Concurrent Programming	Hibernate / EclipseLink / iBatis
Live Migration	Redis
Reactive Programming	MySQL / Postgres
RESTful Web Services	Oracle PL/SQL Development
CI / CD	Gradle / Maven
Jenkins / Buildkite	Git / Subversion
Docker / Docker Compose / Kubernates	Test Driven Development
Apache Kafka / AVRO	JUnit / Mockito
Terraform / Helm	CORE Banking Systems
AWS / SQS / SNS / DynamoDB	Real-Time Financial Systems
GCP / GBQ / CloudSQL / PubSub / Datastream	Trading Systems
Azure Cognitive Search	Supply Chain